Guide to the Burr McIntosh Photograph Collection 1898-1910 PR 41
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. 5 x 7 Prints, ca. 1900 - 1910
  - PORTRAITS
    - Daggett, Mrs. J. H. (2) Dalys, Miss Fraser (8) Davis, Lt. A. H. Davis, Fay (4) Davis, John S. (3) Day, Mrs. H. W. Deals, Mrs. E. J. (3) Demorest Dewart, W. F. (4) Dewitt, John R. Dieterich, Mrs. R. V. (3) Dodge, William E. Dodson, Richard (6) Dominick, G. T. (2) Dougherty, R. K. (2) Douglas, Lady Shafer (6) Donner, P. E. Drake, Mrs. John Draper, J. C. Dresser Dresser, Mrs. D. L. R. Dresser, Martin Dressler, Marie Duclos, R. (2) Dumont (4) Duryea, Mrs. T. W. Dutton, Mrs. B. W. (3) Eastland, J. L. Eastland, Mrs. L. B. Eddy, M. S. (4) Edson, Susan D. (3) Edwards, Col. Eldred Elliott, J. D. Elliott, Maxine Emory, M. V. Emory, Margerite (3) Emory Jr., W. H. Erhardt, J. (3) Ernst, M. W. (3) Escott (6) Fahnstock, Dr. Clarence (2) Faintor, Mrs. C. B. Fargo, J. C. Fargo, S. Farnam (2) Farnum, Mrs. Paulding Farrell Jr., Franklin Filkins Finch, E. (3) Fish, Mrs. A. E. Fisher, E. H. (3) Fisher, Harry A. (5) Fisher, Mrs. R. P. (2) Fisher, T. R. Flackstaff, M. H. (2) Foote, H. A. (2) Forster, Henry A. (2) Frelinhuysen, J. S. (3) Fremsted, Mme. (2) French (2) Freud Frisbie, Miss R. L. (2) Froelich, Bianca (3) Fuller, Ann R. Fuller, H. W. Fuller, Mrs. J. E. (2) Gardner, Mrs. W. B. (2) Gates, Mrs. Charles Gates, Miss M. A. Geraghty Gibney, Dr. (2) Gifford, Maud (2) Gilbert, Cass (2) Gilbert, Mrs. George W. (4) Gilbert, Rev. W. M. Giles, H. W. (2) Gillett Gillett, Mrs. Charles W. Glendenning, E. J. Glover, Miss A. P. (2) Glover, August W. Godfley, E. McM. Gould (3) Gould, Mrs. Howard Graham, Mrs. R. E. Graves, Mrs. W. L. Greanes, Mrs. Tracy (5) Green, Miss M. (2) Green, Mrs. W. H. Greenough, William (2) Griffin, Mrs. J. A. M. (2) Grossmith, Lawrence (4) Grove, W. K. Haden (3) Hagermann, Mr. H. J. (3) Hagerty (3) Haggerty, George V. (2) Hail, H. H. (2) Hall, Blanche Hall, Frank M. Hall Jr., Mrs. W. M. Hamilton, Mrs. C. W., baby (2) Hamilton, G. T. (4) Hamlin, Conde (3) Hammerstein, Mrs. R. (4) Hammett, Mrs. B. M. Haney (3) Hanna Harding, Mrs. E. L. Hardy, L. B. (2) Harper Harriman (3) Harris, Mrs. A. K. (4) Harris, Katherine (7) Harris, Mrs. S. L. Harris, Mrs. Dwight Hart (4) Hartshorne, Katherine B. Harvey, Paul S. Hasbrouck (2) Hatch, W. B. Havemeyer, A. L. (2) Hawes, Florence (3) Hawley, Alan (2) Hay, E. E. Hayes, L. R. (2) Haynes, Mrs. A. D. (2) Hazlett, Madeleine Hegeman, Virginia (2) Heilner, Mrs. M. V. C. (2) Henderson (2) (Offsite-box 9, Folder unknown container)
    - Hickschie, Mrs. A. A. Hill (2) Hilliard, Robert (6) Hills, Miss A. M. (2) Hinsdale, F. G. (2) Haogland, J. A. Hol, Cassie M. Hoff, E. W. (3) Hoffman, M. (5) Holland, Mildred (2) Hollister, Thomas Holt, Mrs. J. S. Holt, Mrs. L. L. Homer, Louise (2) Homer, Capt. C. R. (4) Hooper, Lewis Hopkins, Lydia (2) Houtkock, Vander (2) Howe, H. D. Hoyt, E. (3) Hoyt, F. M. (3) Hoyt, Mrs. J. B. (2) Hoyt, O. (2) Hubbell, George W. Huddlestone, M. (2) Hudnut, Mr. R. C. (4) Huft, Henry Hume, Miss J. A. (3) Huncker, (4) Huneker (4) Hungerford, K. F. (2) Hurd (3) Hurd, F. B. (3) Hurst, Lt. Paul Hutchinson, Mrs. Archibald and son (3) Hyde, Mrs. W. W. Huyler, Mrs. A. V. Ingersoll, H. E. (2) Irwin, Mrs. J. N. Iselin, W. O'D. (4) Ivins, Clinton Jackel, Leonore (2) Jackel, T. B. Jackson James, Mrs. R. H. Jamilson Jay, William Jennings, E. H. Johnson, Mrs. Davis (3) Johnson, E. (3) Jones Kane, E. (6) Keane, James (2) Kendall, William (2) Kennedy, William J. (2) Keyser, Mrs. W. B. and child (4) Kidd, Mary Parson (4) Knight, F. N. Knox, P. C. Koehler, Hugo W. (2) Kreischer, Mrs. George F. Lambart, Ernest Lang, Rev. David Lang, Mathewson (5) Laschelle, Kirk (2) Laughlin, James B. (3) Lavie, Cornelia Laws, F. B. (3) Leary, James D. (2) Leary, James T. (2) Leith, Alex L'Engle Madeleine Levy (3) Liggett, Mrs. T. Livingston, B. W. (5) Lockwood, Mrs. Lockwood, William F. Lonnin, Alice (3) Lounsbury, Edith (2) Lowell, Anne Shipley (3) Luckenback Lyon, J. Dennison Lystix, Dr. C. T. McAdoo (3) McAlton, Lois McCarty, Martin B. (2) McClaren, Percy (2) MacDonald, Christy McEwan, Martin McGann, Mrs. R. Mitchell (2) McGrew, R. A. McIntosh, Burr (5) McKane, John (4) Mackay (4) Mackey (6) McKim, Mrs. Smith H. McMichael, Miss A. T. McMichael, Miss L. C. McMichael, Mrs. L. C. (2) McMillan, Mrs. G. K. Mclyn, Alice (3) Macy, Mrs. O. C. Magee, Mrs. Thomas (2) Maitland, Lady Maltby, F. (3) Manning, J. J. Manton, Jessie M. (2) Marbury, Elizabeth (4) Marks, A. M. (3) Marchall (2) Marston Martin May, Edna (3) Mayo, John C. C. (3) Medarro, Mrs. Henry Mellon, Miss W. L. (2) Mercer, Mrs. Carroll Milliken, Dr. S. M. Mills, Mrs Hepworth (3) Mitchell, A. D. (2) Mitchell, Malcolm (2) Mittencoix, P. W. K. (2) Mittendorf Mixell, B. B. Moehlman, Mr. Moore (6) Moore, A. C. (5) Moore, John W. (2) Morgan child (2) Morgan, W. .F. (4) Morton, Pauline (3) Munseyo, Frank Munson, J. W. (2) Murdock (2) Murray, A. Gordon (2) Murray, Olive (2) Murrison, I. Myers, Marguerite Myles Myles, B. (3) Myles, Dr. Robert C. (2) (Offsite-box 10, Folder unknown container)
    - Nelson, Paul (2) Nevins, A. I. Newman, Marion Oakes Jr., Mrs. F. J. Oakley, Mrs. R. F. Odell, Estelle (2) Ortigan, M. C. (2) Osborn, Mrs Robert (2) Otis (6) Outcault, Mr. R. F. (2) Outhwaite, Mrs. J. H. (2) Overholt, Vinton (2) Page, Florence Page, Howard D. Page, W. H. Page, Mrs. Howard (2) Palmer, Muriel (3) Parker, Olive Parnmore, Mrs. E. E. C. (2) Parr, H. A. Parrott, Mrs. E. F. (5) Parvis, Mr. Peacock, C. N. Peacock, Roland Pearson, E. R. Pell (3) Percival, W. Perrin, Oliver (2) Petree, Simon Pierce, Mrs. W. K. Pitney, Mrs. J. C. H. Plant family, New London (60) Platt (4) Pomeyer, D. G. Porter Porter, Erskine (3) Porter, Mrs. H. F. J. Post, Ethel M. (2) Potter, Clarence (2) Potter, Helen (2) Potter, Dr. W. W. (4) Pratt, Henry A. Preston, Mrs. James (2) Pourtalis, Constance (2) Prussing, Louise (3) Quincy (2) Rand, Mary (2) Randolph, Ellen (2) Rankin, Mrs. J. M. Rapphold, Mme. (5) Rauch, William Reed, Mrs. Legrand (2) Rees (2) Remsen (2) Remsen, Wagstaff (2) Reynolds (3) Reynolds, William H. (3) Rhodes, Mrs. R. (2) Rice, Rev. W. H. Richards, Eben (2) Richards, Dr. G. A. (3) Riggs, R. R. Riker, Mrs. A. P. (3) Rinord, Tyndale Ripley, S. D. (5) Robertson, Mrs. J. A. (3) Robertson, Josephine (2) Robinson (2) Robinson, Mrs. Anson F. (4) Robinson, Beverly (3) Roosevelt, Miss D. L. (3) Roseberry, Augusta C. Runyon, Mrs. Clarson Samaroff, Mme. Olga (6) Sanford, Samuel (4) Sarg, Mrs. Paul Schley, E. B. (2) Schley, K. B. (2) Schouzer, Dr. Fritz (2) Scottie, Antonio (2) Scoville, E. Scoville, L. Scoville, M. F. (2) Scutter, Mrs. J. T. (2) Seagrove, Katherine (2) Sedgewick, Mr. C. S. (2) Sharpe (6) Sherry, D. Sherwood, Phyllis (8) Shevlin (2) Shevlin, T. H. (2) Shevlin, V. W. (3) Shillaber, William Sholley, Jan Silvers, W. Russell (2) Simler, George (2) Simter, Freda Sinclair, Alys (2) Singer, Mrs. Henry W. (3) Six, Capt. P. E. Sizer (3) Skinner Sloan, Mrs. A. Baldwin (2) Smith, Charles E. (2) Smith, F. Vinton (3) Smith, Jewell V. (2) Smith, Karl B. (2) Smith, Martin W. Smith, Proctor (2) Smith, R. A. (2) Smithers, Charles Smithwick, Jones F. Sore, Mrs. Paul O. (2) Sperr, W. K. Stark, Francis Raymond (2) Sterling, Robert V. (2) Stetson, C. M. Stevens, R. M. (3) Stewart, Douglas Stewart, G. M. Stewart, Mrs. J. A. (2) Stillman, C. R. (2) Stinson, Helen (3) Storey, Adele Stuart, Mrs. D. A. Swann, Edward (Offsite-box 11, Folder unknown container)
    - Talbot, H. R. Tallman, Mrs. A. V. Taylor, John I. Taylor, Mrs. William H. Teal, Ben (2) Terry, Mrs. T. L. Thaw, William (3) Theis, Josephine Thomas, A. D. Thomas, Mrs. Addison Throwdy, Mrs. G. F. (2) Tisdale, Mrs. John M. Tod, Mrs. J. Kennedy Todd, M. B. Todd, R. D. Trubenback Truesdale, Mrs. W. H. (4) Tuck, Margaret Twomdy, Mrs M. B. (3) Untermeyer, Mrs. (2) Van Buren, Mrs. I. B. Van Dusen, Mrs. A. C. (2) Van Kleck, Mrs. William H. Van Kloster, Karen Van Riper, Mrs. F. V. Van Riper, K. (4) Van Vaar, C. A. Van Vleck (5) Vandergrift, J. J. (5) Veugiere, E. R. Viele, Francis S. (2) Vogt, E. L. (3) Voorhees, Fred Voree, Virginia (2) Vredenburgh, J. V. Vredenburgh III, Peter Wadsworth, Nellie Walcott (4) Walker, Charlotte Walker, Edith (4) Walker, Jay Walsh, Mrs. (8) Walter, Edwin (3) Walton, E. G. (2) Warfield, Gov. Warfield, Florence Warner, H. B. (4) Warwick, Robert (3) Washington, Mrs. G. A. Weekes, Harold (4) Wendell (3) Wentworth, Mrs. J. W. Westley, John (4) Wheaton, John W. (3) Whife, Nellie V. R. (2) Whitehouse, Julie Whiting, M. W. (2) Whitney, A. E. (3) Whitney, Mrs. Warren (2) Wilcoxson (4) Wilson, Ethel (3) Wilson, Francis (3) Wilson, Harry R. Wilson, R. F. (2) Williamson Winter, A. E. (2) Woodruff, Harry Woods, Allen D. (3) Woodworth, Helen Worth, Elsie (2) Wyatt, Mrs. Stephen (4) Wynant, Frances (2) Yerkes, Mabel (Offsite-box 12, Folder unknown container)
  - SUBJECTS
    - Horse shows (27) Movie-making Philippines (8) Street scene (Offsite-box 12, Folder unknown container)
  - UNIDENTIFIED PORTRAITS
    - Children (19) Groups (21) (Offsite-box 12, Folder unknown container)
    - Men (203) Women (423) (Offsite-box 13, Folder unknown container)
    - Women (con't) (Offsite-box 14, Folder unknown container)
- Series III. 11 x 14 inch Prints, ca. 1900 - 1910
  Series III. 11 x 14 Inch Prints. This series consists of prints divided into three subseries: Portraits, filed alphabetically by sitter; Subjects, filed alphabetically; and Unidentified Portraits divided into groups in exterior settings, groups in interior settings, men, and women. Unlike the other series, identified portraits is the smallest subseries in this series, but does contain portraits of significant people including Theodore Roosevelt, Ethel Barrymore, and William Howard Taft. Theatrical scenes, with costumes and a limited use of set, form an important portion of the subject subseries, including those of Broadway shows with Ethel Barrymore, who is represented in some of the scenes. Other notable images that are unique to this series document the first car show at Madison Square Garden, and school music and sports teams. George P. Hall is also the only credited photographer, outside of Burr McIntosh himself, in this collection, and is represented by his portrait of the Greenwood wedding party in 1900.
  - PORTRAITS
    - Bache, Julia Barrymore, Ethel (5) Marlowe, Julia (2) Nesbit, Evelyn Ritchie, Adele Caruso, Enrico (5) Chester, Arthur Cleveland, Grover (3) Greenwood wedding party (George P. Hall, photographer, ca. 1900) Langerman, James N. S. Roosevelt, Theodore (2) Taft, William Howard (2) (Offsite-box 15, Folder 45)
  - SUBJECTS
    - Baltimore House Show (20) Broadway Board of Trade banquet (Offsite-box 15, Folder 46)
    - Columbia Boat House club house on Hudson River (2) Cuba (9) Mrs. Gilbert's funeral (3) (Offsite-box 15, Folder 47)
    - Houses, exterior (5) First Madison Square Garden Auto Show (5) Manhasset Bay Yacht Club (5) (Offsite-box 15, Folder 48)
    - Morris Park (4) Music groups, predominantly Cornell Glee Club (7) Palm Beach Hotel (9) (Offsite-box 15, Folder 49)
    - Rockaway Hunt club house (4) Sherry's dining room Sport teams, including St. Paul's Hockey Club (13) (Offsite-box 15, Folder 50)
    - Theatrical groups and scenes (54) (Offsite-box 16, Folder 51)
    - Vanderbilt coach (11) (Offsite-box 16, Folder 52)
  - UNIDENTIFIED PORTRAITS
    - Groups, exteriors (4) (Offsite-box 16, Folder 53)
    - Groups, interiors (14) (Offsite-box 17, Folder 54)
    - Men (24) (Offsite-box 17, Folder 55)
    - Women (48) (Offsite-box 17, Folder 56)
- Series IV. Glass Plate Negatives, ca. 1900 - 1910
  Series IV. Glass Plate Negatives This series is divided into two subseries based on size: 5 x 7 inch plates, filed alphabetically by sitter; and 8 x 10, filed alphabetically by sitter, followed by miscellaneous subjects and unidentified portraits. These approximately 600 glass plates are the only remaining negatives from the original 1942 donation. Only a very selected few have been printed; those prints are found in Series I and II. Otherwise, the vast bulk of these images exist only in this format. The majority of this series is made up of portraits, with the only miscellaneous subjects being the Taft trip to the Philippines, hot springs in Virginia, theatrical companies, and the 1906 Yale/Princeton football game.
  The glass plate negatives were once in the negative file but are now reunited intellectually with the Burr McIntosh prints. The prefix is still on the enclosures but is no longer pertinent.
  - 5 X 7 INCH PLATES
    - Abington, W. L. (6) Adams, Maude (5) B-, Eleanor D. Barrymore, Ethel (3) Barrymore, John (2) Bates, Blanche (10) Bellew, Kyrle Belmont, Frances Bentley, Irene (6) Bingham, Amelia Bloodgood (2) Bloodgood, Clara (8) Bloodgood, Mrs.J. (3) Brokaw, H. C. Brokaw, Irving Burton, T. J. (2) Byron, Arthur Cahill Cahill, Miss M. (2) Campbell, Mrs Patrick (7) Carls, Emma (2) Caruso, Enrico (7) Chawnor, R. (Daly's Theatre) Cheatham, Kitty Craigolynne, Mrs. B. Daisy Daly, Arnold Davis, Miss P. (3) Davis, Richard Harding De Angelis, Jefferson (9) De Wolf, Miss G. Douglass (2) Dunne, Peter F. Elliott, Maxine (19) Englande, Ludwig (2) Fahnstock, Dr. Clarence (2) Fealy, Maude Fernandez, Bijou (2) Fieldruff, Harry (3) Finlay (2) Finlay, Mrs. Finlay, G. (4) Fitch, Clyde (3) Fox, Eddie (2) Froelich, Bianca (3) Freustad, Mme. Gibson, Charles Dana (2) Gilbert, Cass (2) Gilbert, Mrs. G. H. (2) Gilbert, H. Gilman, Mabelle (6) Glaser, Lulu (4) Glendenning, John (2) Goodman, Thelma Gould, Mr. (3) Gould, F. J. (2) Green children Green, Charles M. Greene, Daisy Gregory Gregory, Heath (5) Hackett, James K. Haggin, Ben Ali Haines, Mrs. G. G. (3) Hanna, Joseph Harper, Belle Haworth, Joseph (8) Heyer, Miss G. (3) Heyer, Mrs. G. (2) Howard Howard, George W. Hooper, Edna Wallace (12) Hope, Beryl Hohenlohe, Prince (6) Homer, Louise (2) Irving, H. F. Jaimson, Mrs. Jaygard, M. Langtry, Lillie (15) Lansing, R. Lederer Jr., George W. Lewis, Miss. J. Lounsbury, H. R. Loynne, Bassie McIntosh, Burr (2) Maginn, Bonnie (22) Maginn, L. Marlow, Mrs. Marlow, Miss J. Marlow, Julia (2) Metcalfe, James A. (3) Miller, Henry Montenesque, Count Nielson, C. Norris, William (3) Oatman Oatman, E. A. (3) Parson, G. W. (3) Power, Tyrone (3) Rapphold, Mme. (5) Ricardo, Amy (2) Richman, Charles (2) Riggs, Gen.Clinton (3) Robson, Eleanor (25) Rowan, Lansing Saint Saens, Camille (3) Sanaroff, Olga (6) Scheff, Fritzi (7) Schley, E. B. Scotti, Antonio Seygard, Mme. Camille (5) Spong, Hilda (3) Sullivan, John T. Taylor, G. Tesla, Nikola Thom-, L. G. L. Truax, Sarah (3) Tynan, Mr. B (4) Tynan, Mrs. B (3) Vidal, Clarita (5) Walker, Charlotte Warner, Mr. H. B. Westcott, Eva (6) Whiting, Mr. M. W. (2) Whiney, F. C. (2) Wilson, Francis (14) Woodruff (2) Woodruff, Harry (3) Woodruff, Mrs. L. (2) Wynne, Bessie (4) Unidentified (30) (Box Glass)
  - 8 X 10 INCH PLATES
    - Abbott, Bessie (4) Allen, Viola Barrymore, Ethel (3) Barrymore, Jack Barrymore, John (2) Bloodgood Bloodgood, Clara Burke, Billie (2) Campanari Campbell (3) Conquest, Ida De Angelis, Jefferson (3) Edeson, Robert (2) Elliot, Maxine Eustee, Mrs. J. Franko (2) Gillette,William Gould, Majorie Hopper, Edna Wallace (3) Huntley, G. P. Lessing, Madge (3) McIntosh, Burr (2) McKim, C. F. May Miller, Henry Morris, Dave Henner Nadje, Mlle. Nesbit, Evelyn (2) Paetz, John Power, Tyrone Proctor, Catherine Rapphold, Mme. (4) Riley, Mrs. Samaroff, Mme. Sayers, Margaret Schumann-Heinck, Mme. (2) Sembrick Sheldon, Suzanne Spong, Hilda (2) Tarkington, Booth Tynan, B. (3) Van Rooy, Anton Woodruff, Harry Hot Springs, Virginia (4) Taft trip (33) Theatrical companies (Three Little Girls company) (3) Yale/Princeton game, 1906 Unidentified (19) (Box Glass)